# AÍDA ALEJANDRA MARTÍNEZ PALACIOS

4000 Dunwoody Park, Apt 4313 • Atlanta, GA 30338 • 404.960.2062 • aida@juiceanalytics.com

# **SUMMARY**

Master of Science in Analytics graduate with over 6 years of experience on Data Programming and Software Development; Expertise working with large databases, data visualization and predictive modeling. Strong analytical skills and ability to deliver and communicate business insights from data.

#### **EDUCATION**

Georgia State University, J. Mack Robinson College of Business

Atlanta, GA

Master of Science in Analytics

GPA: 4.09/4.3

GPA: 92/100

December 2016

Outstanding Scholar Award

University of Malaga Malaga, Spain

Master of Software Engineering and Artificial Intelligence

September 2012

Merit Based Full Scholarship.

End of degree project: Aurora borealis predictive model using regression and decision trees algorithms.

### Universidad Tecnológica Centroamericana (UNITEC)

Tegucigalpa, Honduras

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 94/100

March 2008

- Graduated with merit; 3<sup>rd</sup> place, class of 2008 (out of 179 undergraduate students)
- Web Technologies and Artificial Intelligence Course, National Tsing Hua University, Taiwan

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Implementations Intern

Atlanta, GA

**Juice Analytics** 

*May 2016 – December 2016.* 

- Developed a text mining model to classify unstructured text into job categories for a healthcare application using Python.
- Created automated ETL processes to extract data from multiple sources to be presented on interactive web dashboards.

### **Data Application Architect**

Atlanta, GA

**Juice Analytics** 

January 2016 – Present

Developed rich data visualizations using Python and JavaScript, allowing clients to extract, share and communicate insights.

#### Graduate Research Assistant

Atlanta, GA

## **Institute for Insight, Georgia State University**

August 2015 - May 2016

- Installed and configured a Hortonworks Hadoop cluster on CentOS.
- Created a predictive model for healthcare claims' arrival time using Decision Trees.
- Created a text mining model for predicting a specific outcome for an U.S. national bank using TF-IDF algorithm on R.

### Business Intelligence Engineer

# **Tigo (Millicom International Cellular)**

Tegucigalpa, Honduras

July 2012 - December 2013

Honduras' #1 Wireless operator with 40 million subscribers globally

- Developed and maintained commercial and accounting reports, as well as created ad-hoc analysis of marketing campaigns and offers for text messaging, microloans and other value added services.
- Designed and developed Microstrategy dashboards for Human Resources, Marketing and Customer Operations, providing insights and daily and monthly KPI's.
- Created a Customer 360° analytical dataset used to build a suite of marketing predictive models.
- Established ETL processes to obtain information from multiple billing and transactional systems using Oracle PL/SQL.

#### Software Developer

Tegucigalpa, Honduras

The Americas Group

April 2008-June 2011

• Developed web and desktop applications for a U.S. Payroll services provider, applying Test Driven Development methodologies using Nunit and Curl.

#### **SKILLS**

**Languages:** Spanish – native, English

**Certifications:** Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist SQL Server 2005, Sun Certified Programmer - Java.

Software Skills: SQL, MongoDB, R, SAS, Python, Tableau, Weka, Microstrategy, Java, .NET, ASP.NET, JavaScript, CSS, Html,

Vega and D3 Visualizations, Elastic Search.

Statistical Skills: Hypothesis Testing, Linear and Logistic Regression, Decision Trees, K-means clustering, Time Series forecasting.